hovercraft: n.  气垫船
Lesson 29 The hovercraft
气垫船
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,然后回答以下问题.
hovercraft: n.  气垫船
What is a hovercraft riding on when it is in motion?
气垫船靠什么行驶?
Many strange new means of transport have been developed in our century,
本世纪已研制出许多新奇的交通工具,
hovercraft: n.  气垫船
the strangest of them being perhaps the hovercraft.
其中最新奇的要数气垫船了.
In 1953,a former electronics engineer in his fifties, Christopher Cockerell,
1953年,有一位50多岁名叫克里斯托弗.科克雷尔的原电子工程师,
Norfolk Broads: n.  诺福克郡的湖泊地区
who had turned to boat-building on the Norfolk Broads,
改行在诺福克郡的湖泊地区从事造船业,
suggested an idea on which he had been working for many years to the British Government and industrial circles.
他提出了他研究多年的一项计划给英国政府和工业界.
cushion: n.  座垫
It was the idea of supporting a craft on a 'pad',or cushion, of lowpressure air,
他的设想是:用一个低压空气垫或软垫来支撑船体
ring: v.  围
ringed with a curtain of higher pressure air.
软垫周围用高压空气环绕.
Ever since,people have had difficulty in deciding
自那以后,人们很难决定
whether the craft should be ranged among ships,planes, or land vehicles--
是否应该将这种运载工具列为轮船、飞机,或是陆上交通工具,
for it is something in between a boat and an aircraft.
因为它是介于船和飞机之间一种东西.
As a shipbuilder,
作为一个船舶技师,
Cockerell was trying to find a solution to the problem of the wave resistance
科克雷尔在寻找解决波浪阻力的方法,
which wastes a good deal of a surface ship's power and limits its speed.
波浪阻力浪费掉了船在水面行驶的大量动力,从而限制了船的速度.
His answer was to lift the vessel out of the water
他的解决办法是把船体提离水面,
cushion: n.  座垫
by making it ride on a cushion of air,no more than one or two feet thick.
让船在一个气垫上行驶,气垫只有一两英尺厚.
ring: v.  围
This is done by a great number of ringshaped air jets on the bottom of the craft.
船底装上大量环状气嘴以实现这一目的.
It 'flies',therefore, but it cannot fly higher--
这样,船就能飞了,但飞不高.
its action depends on the surface,water or ground,over which it rides.
它的飞行取决于它所悬浮的水面或地面.
Solent: n.  （英国的）苏伦特海峡, sensation: n.  轰动
The first tests on the Solent in 1959 caused a sensation.
959年,在苏伦特海峡进行的首次试航引起了轰动.
hovercraft: n.  气垫船
The hovercraft travelled first over the water,then mounted the beach,
气垫船先是在水面上行驶后又登上海岸,
dune: n.  沙丘
climbed up the dunes, and sat down on a road
爬上沙丘,最后停在路上.
Later it crossed the Channel,riding smoothly over the waves,
后来气垫船跨越英吉利海峡,平稳地在波浪上方行驶,
which presented no problem.
波浪不再产生阻力.
Since that time,
从那以后,
hovercraft: n.  气垫船
various types of hovercraft have appeared and taken up regular service.
各种各样的气垫船出现了并开始了定期航行服务.
hovercraft: n.  气垫船
The hovercraft is particularly useful in large areas with poor communications
气垫船在交通不发达地区特别有用,
such as Africa or Australia;
象非洲、澳大利亚等地;
it can become a 'flying fruit-bowl',
它能成为"飞行水果盘子"
plantation: n.  种植园
carrying bananas from the plantations to the ports;
把香蕉从种植园运到港口
hovercraft: n.  气垫船
giant hovercraft liners could span the Atlantic;
大型的气垫班轮或许能跨越大西洋.
hovertrain: n.  气垫火车
and the railway of the future may well be the 'hovertrain',
未来的火车或许能成为"气垫火车",
cushion: n.  座垫
riding on its air cushion over a single rail,which it never touches,
靠气垫在单轨上行驶而不接触轨道,
at speeds,up to 300 m.p.h.--the possibilities appear unlimited.
时速可达每小时300英里.气垫船的前途是不可限量的.